# FAYE ZHANG

Email: zhan1518@umn.edu Tel: 612-5161274 Address: 1512 Vista Club Circle, Apt 202, Santa Clara, CA, 95054

# Please check out my portfolio! https://intelj711.github.io/allAboutMe/allAboutMe.html

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I'm expecting a **Software Engineer** position with this portfolio. Even I'm an engineer at hardware company, I'm doing software development from 3 years ago all the way till now. I've been keeping working on JAVA API development internal product test for 2 years at my current company.

#### **PROFICIENCIES**

- Java(intermediate), C(prior experience)
- Front-End: HTML5/CSS3/Javascript, ES6, React-Redux, JQuery, Bootstrap, Ajax, RESTful API
- Back- End: Node JS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose
- Knowledge of: Sementic-UI, Sass, AngularJS, Google Firebase, GoogleMaps API, Spotify API, Weather Forecast API, etc

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science Electrical Engineering Jul, 2010 – May, 2012 Master of Science Electrical Engineering SEP, 2012 – May, 2014

University of Minnesota-twin cities

University of Minnesota-twin cities

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## SR. RELIABILITY SOFTWARE ENGINEER (SAN JOSE, CA)

April,2016 – Present

- **SK Hynix Memory Solution.** Product Reliability Team.
- Design, develop, optimize and execute regression test cases for enterprise SSD product.
- Work with team to implement reliability test by creating **JAVA** API for internal product reliability test:
  - o Design, develop and maintain test scripts, libraries and cases to show SSD reliability and design maturity
  - o Develop software tools and infrastructure to streamline test process and aid in failure analysis
  - Perform first level failure analysis on the host/link level to understand and articulate failure mode to other engineering functions
  - o Analyze test data collected to provide estimations for product life, reliability and predict failure modes
  - **o** Be gate keeper of product release based on the result of reliability test of 1-day baseline, 1-week mix workload test with temperature condition changing and voltage margin, and 6-week stress RDT.

## PRODUCT AND APPLICATION ENGINEER (SAN JOSE, CA)

Jan, 2015 – April. 2016

- **SK Hynix Memory Solution.** Product and Application Team
- Be responsible of data collecting and reviewing of the mass qualify of SSD product. Created **Python** and **PowerShell** automation script for data parsing and analyzing. Identifying, analyzing, and documenting any defects discovered during testing. Worked with FW or HW engineer on bugs fixing. Supported further discussion with customer through the whole product mass quality.
- Created LUA automation script to measure commands latency and work with FW engineer to get improvement and to meet spec requirement.

#### VALIDATION ENGINEER INTERN (SAN JOSE, CA)

Jan, 2014 – Oct. 2014

- **HGST**, a West Digital Company. Preamp Technology & Characterization Team. Validated multichannel front-end preamp performance and characterization on chip level and HDD level.
- Created **TCL** automation script with GUI to measure chip power consumption while toning through multiple register settings. Worked with validation engineer in Fujisawa head quarter on data review.

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN (PLYMOUTH, MN)

MAY, 2013 – Aug. 2013

- **Nonin Medical**. Firmware Team.
- Worked on development of automation of C script to support test of firmware functionality and validate the accuracy of hardware prototypes for non-invasive medical devices.